Maxwell Patterson

mmpatterson94@gmail.com | 716-525-0522 | Danvers, MA

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxwell-patterson/ | Portfolio: https://mmpatterson.github.io/

SUMMARY

Data Science and Data Visualization professional with a background in consulting. Earned a certificate in Data Science from Northwestern University and have 4+ years of professional experience in data analysis. Educational background includes a B.S. in mathematics and physics from Dickinson College. Experienced in Python, SQL, noSQL, and JavaScript to create full-stack applications. Currently attending the University of Texas- Austin in pursuit of an M.S. in Data Science.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming: Python3 (Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Matplotlib, NumPy, Seaborn, Flask, Requests), SQL (SQL Server, PostgreSQL), noSQL (mongoDB), JavaScript (Plotly, D3, Leaflet), R
- Machine Learning: Decision Trees, Random Forests, Logistic Regression, Linear Regression, Gradient Descent, Stochastic Gradient Descent, Principal Component Analysis, K-Nearest Neighbors, K-Means
- Statistics: Maximum Likelihood Estimation, Expectation Maximization, Bayesian Inference, Bootstrapping
- **Tools**: Tableau, Jupyter Notebooks, APIs (SwaggerUI), HTML5, CSS3, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Visio, Microsoft Visual Studio, Git, SQL Server Management Studio, AWS (S3, RDS)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NIELSENIQ Danvers, MA

Analytical Framework Consultant

August 2019 - Present

- Research NielsenIQ product data to create database prototypes based on the needs of retailers and manufacturers in the CPG industry. Meet with client SMEs to confirm databases meet contractual requirements
- Lead project that uses Python and SQL, while partnering with non-technical stakeholders, to develop reports using product information from both database and API data sources. These reports have built-in data validation functionality based on use cases, and they reduce manual analysis time by 95%
- Member of an efficiency team within the organization that aims to identify current processes that can be streamlined in order to reduce the length of product delivery timelines

TRILOGY EDUCATION SERVICES

Chicago, IL

Teaching Assistant, Data Visualization Program

April 2020 – August 2020

- Assisted students in a 24-week boot camp that teaches them Python, SQL, noSQL, JavaScript, Tableau, and machine learning concepts
- Reviewed and graded code submitted by students. Provided feedback in a timely manner

REVENUE SOLUTIONS, INC.

Chicago, IL

IT Consultant

December 2017 - August 2019

Associate IT Consultant

September 2016 - December 2017

- Received company award for excellence in communication with the client
- Used SQL Server to provide Production support for web applications that improve tax processing efficiency for three separate state, city, and county government agencies
- Frequently led meetings with client teams to discuss progress on product enhancements
- Designed software requirement specifications (SRS) for multiple custom interfaces involving ETL, providing access to more external data for clients

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS- AUSTIN Master of Science, Data Science

Cumulative GPA: 3.84

January 2021 – Present

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY Certificate, Data Science Boot Camp

August 2019 - February 2020

DICKINSON COLLEGE

Bachelor of Science, Mathematics and Physics

August 2012 - May 2016

PROJECTS

WORLDWIDE EARTHQUAKE TRACKER

Github Link: https://github.com/mmpatterson/leaflet-earthquake-tracker

Link to Deployed Project: https://mmpatterson.github.io/leaflet-earthquake-tracker/earthquake-tracker/

- A site that displays information for earthquakes that have occurred within the last 7 days
- Using public data, plotted the location of each earthquake on a Leaflet map and scaled its size based on the severity of the event
- The map was created using Leaflet.js, and the API providing the data was made available by the United States Geological Survey

RIDESHARE PRICE PREDICTOR

Github Link: https://github.com/atomazos/machine learning-ridesharing data

Link to Deployed Project: https://chi-ride.herokuapp.com/

- An app that uses an SGD Regression machine learning model to predict rideshare fares in Chicago, IL
- Using public rideshare data made available by the City of Chicago, I made the SGD Regression model based off of pickup location, drop-off location, weather, and time of day
- The machine learning model was created in Python, the visualizations were made using D3.js, and the app was deployed to Heroku

CHICAGO BUILDING ENERGY EFFICIENCY

Github Link: https://github.com/mmpatterson/chicago-buildings

Link to Deployed Project: https://mmpatterson.github.io/chicago-buildings/index.html

- A site that analyzes the energy efficiency of large buildings in Chicago, IL based on the age, location, and size of the buildings
- Using public data, I made two map visualizations: one plots buildings by age and the other plots buildings by energy efficiency
- The maps were created using Leaflet is, and the API supplying the data was provided by the City of Chicago